<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Plugged In]]></title>
  <link href="http://mbombick.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mbombick.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-22T19:16:45-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://mbombick.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mark Bombick]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introduced to Ruby on Rails]]></title>
    <link href="http://mbombick.github.io/blog/2014/06/22/introduced-to-ruby-on-rails/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-22T14:15:56-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mbombick.github.io/blog/2014/06/22/introduced-to-ruby-on-rails</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My first revelation of the power of rails came from Start Norfolk.  Start Norfolk is a 72 hour weekend hackathon/startup event.  Developers, designers, engineers, entrepreneurs, business consultants, investors, scientists, professors, students, and anyone with an interest in learning, building, and developing technology come together to pitch, build, and compete for funding.</p>

<p>Start Norfolk was hatched by Zack Miller and Brennen Dunn with the We are Titans team in 2011.  I was introduced to their idea by management professor and advisor, Mike Provance at ODU.  Their event was filled with seminars, mentors, and productive refreshments!</p>

<p>My introduction to rails came from this startup event in 2011.  Wall signage in the industrial space read &ldquo;HTML5&rdquo; &amp; &ldquo;Rails&rdquo;.  I remember asking myself, HTML5?  &ldquo;The same HTML I would use to get burning text on myspace? Rails?&rdquo;  I was starting to draw blanks.  Where have I been?  My ability to view things from a macro and micro level supposdedly gave me a informed global view that took Porters 5 Forces into account and looked to offer a solid value proposition.  Realization hit. No one cares how much you know about the news and how smart you are about your analysis &amp; conclusions.  How long you&rsquo;ve stayed up looking at company 10K&rsquo;s &amp; 10Q&rsquo;s doing excel charts.  They want tangible products with intangible services to benefit their investment.  Things they can view, touch, and interact with.  I knew I would have to improve my skills.  I was years behind.  I remember building simple HTML homepages hosted on a old IBM tower, visual basic calculators, twisting CAT5 and crimping my RJ45&rsquo;s to make network cables for my Cisco network topologies modules in highschool.  But my technical skills were vastly subpar to those in the profressional technology world.</p>

<p>As east coast as it gets. Being a corporate career minded individual.  I was out of my league with professionals who build, develop, create, and maintain things and in turn gaining a profit.  How else could they sustain their livelihood?</p>

<p>How naive of me to think building a fully functional feature rich application was going to be an easy task.  No money, no team, no technical skills, no profressional network.  My state of being was information hungry and I read anything related to changes in economics, socioeconomics, and technology. Including articles from Business Insider, HBR, MIT Tech Review, Mashable, Techcrunch and numerous other tech/personal blogs.</p>

<p>But I thought to myself after my Start Norfolk experience.  The team who won didn&rsquo;t have the most dazzling product, app, or service.  What they did have, produce, and deliver was a demo.  This was my &ldquo;ah hah&rdquo; moment.  I finally grasped the concept of coding, programming, developing, and the uses of the rails framework.  You do not have to be a savant to code, but you have to be diligent.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Octo Basics Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://mbombick.github.io/blog/2014/06/22/octo-basics-post/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-22T13:27:33-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mbombick.github.io/blog/2014/06/22/octo-basics-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey, this is initial content.  Lorum Ipsum.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
