<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Norfolk | Mark Bombick]]></title>
  <link href="http://mbombick.github.io/blog/categories/norfolk/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mbombick.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-23T17:35:35-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://mbombick.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mark Bombick]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Programming Comprehension and Rails Development]]></title>
    <link href="http://mbombick.github.io/blog/2014/06/22/introduced-to-ruby-on-rails/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-22T14:15:56-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mbombick.github.io/blog/2014/06/22/introduced-to-ruby-on-rails</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My first revelation of the power of Ruby on Rails was unveiled at Start Norfolk 2011.  Start Norfolk is a 72 hour weekend hackathon/startup event.  Gathering developers, designers, engineers, entrepreneurs, business consultants, investors, scientists, professors, and students.  Anyone with an interest in learning, building, and developing technology. The diverse set of contributors come prepared to pitch, build, and compete for seed funding.</p>

<p>Start Norfolk was hatched by Zack Miller and Brennan Dunn with the We are Titans team in 2011.  I was introduced to Zack &amp; Brennan&rsquo;s idea by professor and advisor, Dr. Provance at Old Dominion.  Their event was exciting and diverse.  Filled with informative seminars, demos, mentors, and productive refreshments.  For example, a team who did a crowdfunding round on Kickstarter featured an amazing product for homebrewing.  Just for context, they were presenting in front of a crowd drinking ice cold beer from red solo cups.  Really glad it wasn&rsquo;t about the packet manager. Instead, Beerbug gave fermentation info to brewers of Pilsners, Ales, and Stouts.</p>

<p>My introduction to rails came from this startup event in 2011.  Wall signage in the industrial space of the Innovation Research Park read &ldquo;HTML5&rdquo; &amp; &ldquo;Rails&rdquo;.  I remember asking myself. &ldquo;HTML5? The same HTML I would use to get burning text on myspace? What is Ruby on Rails?&rdquo;  I was starting to draw blanks.  My years of schooling taught me to view situations from a macro and micro level.  My mental models pinging Porter&rsquo;s 5 Forces, various 2x2 matrices, and the industry value chain to continuously improve efficiency lagged.  Realization hit. My knowledge of current events along with the analysis &amp; conclusions that followed were not enough.  Leveraging hours spent inspecting company 10K &amp; 10Q filings performing fundamental excel functions was not sufficient. I wanted to give people tangible products with intangible services to benefit their investment.  Things they can view, touch, and interact with.  My skills would have to improve.</p>

<p>How naive of my lines of thinking regarding programming.  Building a fully functional feature rich application were hyper iterative dreams.  Needing a medium to make those dreams reality was the missing link.  With no money, no team, no technical skills, no profressional network.  I was information hungry.  Reading anything related to changes in domestic and international economics, socioeconomics, and technology. Articles from Gigaom, Business Insider, HBR, MIT Tech Review, Mashable, Techcrunch, inlcuding numerous other tech/personal blogs and mainstream media programming.<br/>
Technology has been ingrained in my life since a young age.  Building simple HTML homepages hosted on an old IBM tower, visual basic calculators, memories learning about data, twisting CAT5 and crimping my RJ45&rsquo;s to make network cables for Cisco networks in highschool.  My technical skills were vastly subpar to those in the profressional technology world.  I was out of my league with professionals who build, develop, create, and maintain products/services gaining a profit.  How else could they sustain their livelihood?</p>

<p>I thought to myself after my Start Norfolk experience.  The winning team didn&rsquo;t have the most dazzling product, app, or service from my perspective.  What they did own, produce, and deliver was a demo. TutoriAll.  This was my &ldquo;ah hah&rdquo; moment.  I finally grasped the concept of coding, programming, developing, and the uses of languages in particular the rails framework.</p>

<p>You do not have to be a savant to code, but you have to be diligent.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
